# JOSEPH STEVEN YAKUBU

Address: 53 Main Avenue, Aldenco Estate, Galadimawa, Abuja. +2348170683343, +2348078082313 | JosephStevenYakubu@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Meticulous and service-oriented Software and Network Engineer with an academic background in Information Technology and Systems and over 6 years of experience in securing and stabilizing computing infrastructure, network communication, and providing ongoing technical support and solution with quick and efficient turn-around. Able to clearly understand problems and find positive solutions through the utilization of troubleshooting, critical thinking, teamwork and communication. Proven experience in translating complex subject material into clear, understandable solution for target audience. Organized and able to work within multiple teams to provide solutions and blend a rich mix of detail with planning and goal - setting acumen.

#### **CAREER ACHIEVEMENT**

- Extended functionality of HR applications and access to mobile devices which resulted in 70% increase in productivity.
- Reduced expenditure on monthly internet subscription by 50%.
- Achieved a resolution rate of 100% for IT related incidences for 6 consecutive months.
- Developed several modules of an Enterprise Resource Planning application.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

TTC Mobile Limited Oct 2020 – Till Date

IT Apprenticeship (Internship)

- Microsoft Server Administration
- Linux Server Administration
- Cloud Solution Architecture
- DevOps Engineering

### Hannibal and Ataturk Co. Limited, Abuja, FCT

Oct 2019 - Sept 2020

**IT Engineer** 

- Installing, configuring and maintaining computer hardware, operating systems and applications.
- Performing troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer systems faults and wireless local area network issues (LAN).
- Setting up wireless local area networks and configuring network devices to ensure effective functionality.
- Carrying out design, development and administration of websites.
- Providing strategic advice, IT assistance and recommendations to staff on the use of technology to achieve organizational goals and improve business processes.

# Adkan Group, Abuja, FCT

Feb 2019 – Sep 2019

IT Manager

- Installing, configuring and maintaining computer hardware, CCTV, operating systems and applications.
- Performing troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer systems faults, wired and wireless local and wide area network issues (LAN, WLAN and WAN).
- Setting up wired and wireless local area networks and configuring network devices to ensure effective functionality.
- Effectively set up and disables user accounts and profile for staffs on the Domain, Active Directory (AD) and Microsoft Dynamics 2012 (ERP).
- Carrying out design, development and administration of websites for the group and subsidiaries.

- Providing strategic advice, IT assistance and recommendations to staff on the use of technology to achieve organizational goals and improve business processes.
- Monitoring application and database servers and perform daily backups of data.

## MacAdams Technologies Limited, Abuja, FCT

July 2018 - Dec 2018

IT Help Desk Engineer

- Installed, configured and maintained computer hardware, operating systems and applications.
- Performed troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer systems faults, wired and wireless local and wide area network issues (LAN, WLAN and WAN)
- Configured and set-up new devices for staffs and adding them to Active Directory.
- Maintained and prioritized records/logs of repairs and fixes and maintenance schedule and escalate where necessary.
- Facilitated the set-up ICT related equipment for meetings, training, seminars and video conferencing events.

## Saanet Soft Nigeria Limited, Kaduna

Nov 2016 - March 2018

Software/Web Developer

- Created applications that address the phases of software development life cycle (SDLC).
- Gathered and refined specifications and requirements based on technical needs and analyse to influence the design.
- Wrote well designed, testable, efficient and documented code by utilizing best software development best practices.
- Identified problems uncovered by customer feedback and testing, and devise possible solutions to anticipated problems.
- Developed and validated exhaustive test routines, plans and schedules to ensure that test cases imitate external interfaces.
- Created website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS practices.

#### **Emerging Trees Limited, Kaduna**

April 2016 - Nov 2016

**IT Support Officer** 

- Installed, configured and maintained computer hardware, operating systems and applications.
- Performed troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer systems faults, wired and wireless local and wide area network issues (LAN, WLAN and WAN)
- Set-up ICT related equipment for training and kept track/Inventory of IT assets and infrastructure.
- Performed weekly backup of database, documentation and report of activities.

### Wadi Ben Hirki Foundation

June 2015 - Present

Ad Hoc/IT Support Staff (Web Designer & Social Media Manager)

- Responsible for the design, development, and maintenance of the current website.
- Optimized content towards revenue driving activities and drive traffic to the site.
- Edited, uploaded and published web content, as well as updated a wide variety of website features.

### National Environmental Standards and Regulations Enforcement Agency (NESREA), Kano

IT Officer / Program Analyst

Dec 2014 - Feb 2016

- Created and maintained the database of facilities in the Region.
- Installed, configured and maintained computer hardware, operating systems and applications.
- Responsible for troubleshooting to diagnose and resolve computer systems faults, wired network issues.

### Visual Solutions Sdn Bhd, Malaysia

Feb 2012 - Nov 2012

Web/Software Developer

- Created applications that address the phases of software development life cycle (SDLC)
- Gathered and refined specifications and requirements based on technical needs and analyse to influence design.
- Developed and validated exhaustive test routines, plans and schedules to ensure that test cases imitate external interfaces.
- Created website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS practices.

#### **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

- Professional Diploma (DNIIT) Master Mind Series, NIIT.
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (Microsoft Server 2012 R2), Emerging Trees Limited, Kaduna.
- Oracle Certified Associate (Oracle Database 12c), Emerging Trees Limited, Kaduna.
- CompTIA A+ and N+ (Hardware, Operating System Concepts and Network Fundamentals), NIIT.
- Professional Digital Marketing, Digital Marketing Skills Institute.

#### **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION**

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), Cisco Systems Inc.
- Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012/2014 (70 461), Microsoft Certified Professional.
- Installing and Configuring Microsoft Server 2012 R2 (70 410), Microsoft Certified Professional.
- A+, CompTIA.

#### **EDUCATION**

•	Bachelors of Information Technology and Systems  Monash University	2013
•	<b>DNIIT in Software Engineering</b> NIIT	2008

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle
- Programming / Scripting Languages: C# & VB.NET, ASP.NET, XML, HTML 5 & CSS3, JavaScript, Python
- Operating Systems: Apple Mac OSX, Windows Server and Client OS, Linux
- Monitoring & Evaluation.
- Reporting and documentation.